export const chapter = "Chapter - 4: Rural Life and Society";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary objective of the East India Company when it came to India?",
        optionA: "Ensuring the welfare of the Indian people",
        optionB: "Promoting social and cultural development",
        optionC: "Making a profit and earning money",
        correctAnswer: "c) Making a profit and earning money",
      },
      {
        question: "How did the Company affect rural life in India?",
        optionA: "It had no significant impact on rural life.",
        optionB:
          "It made a great impact on rural life in terms of agriculture and economy.",
        optionC: "It focused on improving rural infrastructure and services.",
        correctAnswer:
          "b) It made a great impact on rural life in terms of agriculture and economy.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What system did the Company implement in Bengal and Bihar to collect land revenue?",
        optionA: "Permanent Settlement",
        optionB: "Mahalwari System",
        optionC: "Ijardari System",
        correctAnswer: "c) Ijardari System",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which system fixed land revenue on a permanent basis and turned small rulers into landlords?",
        optionA: "Permanent Settlement",
        optionB: "Mahalwari System",
        optionC: "Ryotwari System",
        correctAnswer: "a) Permanent Settlement",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What social class emerged as a result of the Permanent Settlement system?",
        optionA: "Wealthy peasants",
        optionB: "Landless farmers",
        optionC: "Landlords",
        correctAnswer: "c) Landlords",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In which system did the peasants pay land revenue individually, and the rate was as high as fifty percent of the total produce?",
        optionA: "Ijardari System",
        optionB: "Permanent Settlement",
        optionC: "Ryotwari System",
        correctAnswer: "c) Ryotwari System",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How did the colonial agrarian policy affect the peasants' income?",
        optionA: "It increased their income significantly.",
        optionB: "It left them with a meager income due to high land revenue.",
        optionC: "It had no impact on their income.",
        correctAnswer:
          "b) It left them with a meager income due to high land revenue.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What crops did the British East India Company encourage farmers to produce to serve their dual purpose of revenue and raw materials?",
        optionA: "Food grains",
        optionB: "Cash crops",
        optionC: "Livestock",
        correctAnswer: "b) Cash crops",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What impact did the cultivation of cash crops have on the land?",
        optionA: "It made the land more fertile.",
        optionB: "It rendered the land infertile over time.",
        optionC: "It had no impact on the land's fertility.",
        correctAnswer: "b) It rendered the land infertile over time.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary cause of the first major peasant revolt in Bengal?",
        optionA: "High rates of land revenue",
        optionB: "Shortage of food grains",
        optionC: "Foreign invasions",
        correctAnswer: "a) High rates of land revenue",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The East India Company came to India primarily for _____________ and making money, with little concern for people's welfare.",
        optionA: "trade",
        optionB: "cultural exchange",
        optionC: "industrial development",
        correctAnswer: "trade",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Company's officers were often more interested in their own ___________ than the welfare of the people.",
        optionA: "prosperity",
        optionB: "political influence",
        optionC: "cultural values",
        correctAnswer: "prosperity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Company's colonial agrarian policies had a significant impact on rural life, affecting professional, social, cultural, and ___________ aspects.",
        optionA: "technological",
        optionB: "economic",
        optionC: "educational",
        correctAnswer: "economic",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Company acquired diwani rights in Bengal in _______ after its victories in the battles of Plassey and Buxar.",
        optionA: "1757",
        optionB: "1765",
        optionC: "1771",
        correctAnswer: "1765",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The revenue systems during this period included the Ijardari System, Permanent Settlement, Mahalwari System, and ___________ System.",
        optionA: "Zemindari",
        optionB: "Ryotwari",
        optionC: "Taxation",
        correctAnswer: "Ryotwari",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Ijardari System was initially continued by the Company in Bengal, where revenue officials collected land revenue, deducted 10 percent as commission, and deposited the rest in the ___________.",
        optionA: "Company's treasury",
        optionB: "local temple",
        optionC: "farmers' cooperative",
        correctAnswer: "Company's treasury",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Permanent Settlement system was introduced in Bengal and Bihar in _______.",
        optionA: "1793",
        optionB: "1801",
        optionC: "1810",
        correctAnswer: "1793",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Under the Permanent Settlement, small rulers were made ___________ and the revenue they had to pay to the Company was fixed on a permanent basis.",
        optionA: "farmers",
        optionB: "landlords",
        optionC: "government officials",
        correctAnswer: "landlords",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mahalwari System, introduced in western Uttar Pradesh, parts of Madhya Pradesh, and Punjab, vested land ownership in a 'revenue estate' called ___________.",
        optionA: "Taluka",
        optionB: "Mahal",
        optionC: "Zamindar",
        correctAnswer: "Mahal",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the Ryotwari System, individual peasants were recognized as the owner of the land and were required to pay land revenue ___________.",
        optionA: "collectively",
        optionB: "individually",
        optionC: "to the Zamindars",
        correctAnswer: "individually",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The East India Company's primary interest in India was profit, with little concern for people's welfare.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The colonial agrarian policies of the East India Company had no significant impact on rural life.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The Company acquired diwani rights in Bengal in 1757.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Permanent Settlement system was introduced in Bengal and Bihar in 1793.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Ryotwari System required individual peasants to pay land revenue collectively.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mahalwari System was introduced in Punjab, parts of Madhya Pradesh, and western Uttar Pradesh.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Company's colonial agrarian policies led to an increase in agricultural production and prosperity among farmers.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Permanent Settlement system resulted in a new social class of landlords.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Company introduced machine-made goods that had lower quality and higher prices compared to locally crafted goods.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Many significant peasant revolts took place in different parts of India as a result of the East India Company's revenue policies.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
